globalsecurity.org 2019-06-01

# GlobalSecurity.org - Privacy Policy

The GlobalSecurity.org privacy policy is clear: We will collect no personal information about you when you visit our website unless you choose to provide that information to us.

Web servers serving GlobalSecurity.org automatically collect certain non-personally identifiable information, such as which pages each user visits and the domain name (e.g., earthlink.net) of visitors. This information is used for various purposes including internal review and for traffic audits. We also provide this information about our users on an aggregated, anonymous basis to our advertisers.

If you do nothing during your visit but browse through the website, read pages, or download information, we will gather and store certain information about your visit automatically. This information does not identify you personally. We automatically collect and store only the following information about your visit:

The Internet domain (for example, "xcompany.com" if you use a private Internet access account, or "yourschool.edu" if you connect from a university's domain) and IP address (an IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer whenever you are surfing the Web) from which you access our website.

  * The type of browser and operating system used to access our site;
  * The date and time you access our site;
  * The pages you visit; and
  * If you linked to the GlobalSecurity.org website from another website, the address of that website.

We use this information to help us make our site more useful to visitors-to learn about the number of visitors to our site and the types of technology our visitors use. We do not track or record information about individuals and their visits.

Third Party Advertising

We use BUDS INC and other third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Web site. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements on this site and other sites about goods and services that may be of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please [click here ](http://www.networkadvertising.org/optout_nonppii.asp)

Third Party Cookies

In the course of serving advertisements to this site, our third-party advertiser may place or recognize a unique “cookie” on your browser.

We send to your web browser many of the advertisements you see when you use our network of Web sites. However, we also allow other companies, called third-party ad servers or ad networks, to serve advertisements within our web pages. Because your web browser must request these advertising banners from the ad network Web site, these companies can send their own cookies to your cookie file, just as if you had requested a web page from the site. Please note that if an advertiser asks us to show an advertisement to a certain audience (for example, men ages 18-34) or audience segment (for example, men ages 13-24 who have viewed sports content) and you respond to that ad, the advertiser or ad-server may conclude that you fit the description of the audience they are trying to reach. As always remember, we only authorize our third-party ad servers to employ anonymous cookies for ad delivery and anonymous targeting. Our third-party ad servers do not collect, nor do we give them access, to any personally identifying information about you. 

This web site participates in Six Apart Media, a comprehensive advertising program provided by Six Apart Ltd. for publishers all across the Web. This section of our privacy policy describes how Six Apart Ltd. and the third party advertising networks and advertisers that display advertisements through Six Apart Media (collectively, "Advertisers") collect, use, store and disclose data from visitors to this Web site.

A "cookie" is a small amount of data, which often includes an anonymous unique identifier that is sent to your browser from a Web site's computers and stored on your computer's hard drive. Cookies can be used to target advertisements relevant to your interests, based on your visits to different Web sites, to provide traffic measurement and other analytics and to conduct research. 

A "Web beacon" is an electronic file on a Web page that allows a Web site to count users who have visited that page, to access certain cookies and to provide auditing, research and reporting for advertisers. 

When your browser requests a page that displays advertising from one of the Advertisers, the Advertiser may view, edit or set its own cookie through your browser. In addition, the Advertiser may place its own Web beacon in the page, which may be triggered by your browser's request.

Advertiser Privacy Policies

If you would like to contact the Advertisers to learn more about their privacy policies and what options (if any) they offer to opt out of their data collection and use, please follow these links to their Web sites:

Six Apart Ltd. 

http://www.sixapart.com/privacy

Six Apart Media third party advertising networks and advertisers 

http://www.sixapart.com/advertising/solutions-for-bloggers/privacy/3rd-party-list/index.html 

Legitimate Interest

Exponential Interactive, Inc, as our partner, have a legitimate interest to collect and profile personal data in the form of IP address and cookie ID from users on our website in order to provide targeted online advertising and ad measurement. For more details including opt-out requests, access requests or complaints, please review [their privacy policy ](http://exponential.com/privacy/)or contact their data protection officer via privacy@exponential.com.

Piano Software, Inc., New York, US processes your personal data for the product improvement, maintenance and testing purposes based on the legitimate interest pursuant to the Article 6(1)(f) of the GDPR and for the statistical purposes pursuant to the Article 89 GDPR as a data controller. The legitimate interest pursued by Piano Software, Inc. is the ability to improve and develop its own software solutions. Recipients of your personal data include staff of Piano group entities located in the EU, the US and Russia and employees staff of other sub-contractors (mainly hosting and cloud providers for Piano software) located in the EU and the US. Such transfer to third countries is based on model clauses adopted between Piano and the above parties. Piano is also EU-US Privacy Shield certified. Such processing will only occur as long as you continue to use our services. As a data controller, Piano does not process any special categories of personal data, does not monetize personal data and does not perform automated individual decision-making. If you have any question about Piano’s processing of personal data, please visit www.piano.io/privacy or contact Piano directly at privacy@piano.io. Please note we are not entitled to handle your request if your request is related to purposes pursued by Piano as a data controller. You may also lodge a complaint at the Office of Personal Data Protection in Slovakia, where the EU establishment of Piano is located (https://dataprotection.gov.sk/uoou/en). Nothing prevents you to lodge compliant elsewhere. For clarity, we use Piano as a data processor to support our services we provide to you. When selecting Piano as a data processor, we have accessed the guarantees provided by Piano to comply with the GDPR. This information is required because Piano legitimately process your personal data for their own above-mentioned purposes of processing as well. 

Opting Out of Third-Party Ad Servers

If you want to prevent a third-party ad server from sending and reading cookies on your computer, you must visit each ad network's Web site individually and opt out (if they offer this capability). 

Some of these third party advertising networks are participants in the Network Advertising Initiative ("NAI"), a cooperative of online marketing and analytics companies committed to building consumer awareness and establishing responsible business and data management practices and standards. You can learn more about NAI and how you may "opt out" of targeted advertising delivered by NAI member ad networks.

The [Network Advertising Initiative Opt-out Tool](http://networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) was developed in conjunction with member advertising networks with the express purpose of allowing consumers to "opt out" of the targeted advertising delivered by these networks. Using this tool, you can examine your computer to see which ad networks have placed a cookie file on your PC. You may also review each NAI member's privacy policy. To opt out of an NAI member advertising program, simply check the box that corresponds to the company from which you wish to opt out and then press the "Submit" button at the bottom of the page. The tool will automatically replace the specified cookie(s) and verify your opt out status. 

Opting out of a network does not mean you will no longer receive online advertising. It does mean that the network from which you opted out will no longer deliver ads tailored to your Web preferences and usage patterns. The NAI Opt-out Tool is cookie-based. In order for the tool to work on your computer, your browser must be set to accept 3rd party cookies. If you buy a new computer, change Web browsers or delete this cookie, you will need to perform the opt-out task again. Apple presets the Safari browser to block cookies from sites other than those you visit directly. As a result, the NAI opt out tool, which uses third party cookies, will not work for browsers left in this default setting. 

* * *
